(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-06T12:18:18.439684",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
火の用心じゃ〜！
Watch out for fires!
あらあら〜？めらめら〜？
Ara ara~? Mera mera~?
熱干めら〜！！
Atsuchi Mera!!
ホロライブ アソビ☆まわり隊！ご利益担当の火消し屋サラマンダー
Fortune-blessed firefighter salamander of the Hololive Play Around Team!
熱干めらなのだ！
I am Atsuchi Mera!
みなさん、はじめまして！！
Hello everyone, nice to meet you!!
2026年9月24日にホロライブからデビューしたピカピカの新米VTuberなのだ〜！
I'm a brand-new rookie VTuber who debuted from Hololive on September 24, 2026,
ピカピカの新米VTuberなのだ〜！
sparkling and brand-new!
今日はわしの自己紹介動画を撮っていこうと思うのじゃ！
Today, I'm going to shoot my self-introduction video!
わしのこと「どんな子かな〜？」とか気になったり「人間じゃないの？」とか「なんで髪の毛燃えてるの？」とか
If you're wondering "What kind of girl is she?", "Isn't she human?", or "Why is her hair on fire?",
ホロライブのオーディションを受けた時の話とかもしようかなって思っているので
or even stories about when I auditioned for Hololive,
この動画を見てわしのこといっぱい知ってくれたら嬉しいのじゃ！
I hope you'll watch this video and get to know all about me!
ということで動画スタート！！
So without further ado, let's start the video!!
名前はあっちちめら、
My name is Atsuchi Mera,
「ねっせん」じゃないのじゃ！
not "Nessen"!
「あっちち」って読むのじゃ！
You read it as "Atsuchi"!
「千度の熱」と書いて「熱干（あっちち）」良い名前なのだ！
It's written with the kanji for "thousand degrees of heat" as "Atsuchi." What a great name!
そして「めら」、メラメラのめらなのだ！火が燃えている時の
And "Mera" comes from "meramera," the sound of a fire burning!
オノマトペ、擬音？みたいなやつなのだ！
It's like an onomatopoeia for flames.
漢字がちょっと分かりづらいのと、あと辞書で一発で出てこないので、めら組のお主らは
Since the kanji is a bit tricky and doesn't pop up right away in dictionaries, my Mera-gumi subjects...
熱干（あっちち）を辞書登録していつでも熱干（あっちち）を呼び出せるようにしてほしいなじょ。
should add "Atsuchi" to your smartphone dictionaries so you can type it anytime!
そしてお主らが気になっているであろう種族！
And now for the species you've all been wondering about!
わしはサラマンダーなのだ！
I am a salamander!
見てこのツノ、ツノ、あと、尻尾なのだ〜！
Look at these horns... and my tail!
どうかの？かわいいかの？
Cute, aren't they?
サラマンダーとは火を司る精霊らしいのじゃ！
A salamander is said to be a spirit that rules over fire!
わしの髪の毛からもね、こうやって炎が出ておるじゃろ？
As you can see, flames come out of my hair like this.
これはね、体内の熱をどこかから出さないと、わしが火を吹いちゃって周りを火だらけにしちゃうから、
This is because if I don't release my internal heat, I'd end up breathing fire and setting everything around me ablaze!
こうやって髪から出すことで、火を暴発しないようにしているんじゃ。
So I let the fire out through my hair to prevent explosions.
わし的には正直人間と変わらんくね？と思っているところがあって、
Honestly, I think I'm not that different from humans.
火に強いとはいいつつも、火傷はするのじゃ。
I mean, while I'm strong against fire, I can still get burned!
手とか指とかは火傷しないんだけど、粘膜は火傷しちゃうから、それこそベロとかあったかいココアとか飲む時は、
My hands and fingers don't get burned, but my mucous membranes do—like when I drink hot cocoa and burn my tongue!
ベロ火傷しちゃって熱くなるのじゃ。
I end up burning my tongue and it hurts!
あと炎属性なんじゃが、夏はめちゃくちゃ暑いのだ！日本の夏やばいのじゃ。
And though I have a fire attribute, Japanese summers are ridiculously hot!
湿度とかもあるからかな？やばいから熱中症になるのじゃ熱中症。
With the humidity and all, it's so bad I get heatstroke!
サラマンダーなのに！熱中症とか火傷とかそういうのならないようにすればいいのに なー。
Even though I'm a salamander, I really wish I wouldn't get heatstroke or burns...
わしはあと火を吹いたりできるのだ！
I can also breathe fire!
火を吹くときはね、デビューした時、あの情報解禁の時に上げてる映像に火をね吹いてるねアニメーションがあってね、それをみてほしいのだ。わしのカッコいいところが見れるかも知れないのだ。
If you want to see my cool fire-breathing side, check out the PV released during my information unban!
わしの年齢は415歳！長生きなのだ〜。
My age is 415 years old! I've lived a long time~.
生年月日いうと、1611年の4月16日生まれなのだ。
In terms of birthdate, I was born on April 16, 1611.
何年何月何日とか言ったんじゃが、厳密には覚えてなくて、大体江戸時代だった気がするのだ。
I gave a specific year, month, and day, but I don't really remember it—I just feel like it was around the Edo period.
あとわしは良い子だから、415(よいこ)歳ってことにしようと思って、割と適当？415歳ってことにしようと思って、
Also, since I'm a good kid ("yoiko" = 415), I decided to make my age 415 years old! Pretty arbitrary, right?
そっから逆算することによって、1611年生まれになったということじゃ。そういうことじゃ。
And then worked backward to get my birth year as 1611. That's just how it is!
全部うろ覚えなのだ！そんな何百年も前のことを覚えてる訳ないのだ！
There's no way I could remember things from hundreds of years ago!
まおっさ400歳ぐらいだと思っていただければ良いのかなと思うのだ。
Just think of me as about 400 years old and you'll be fine.
そして400年前わしが生まれたての頃何していたかと言うと、火消しという職業をしていたのだ！
As for what I was doing 400 years ago when I was born, I worked as a firefighter!
火消しってのは現代でいうところの消防団みたいなの。文字通り火を消すのだ。
Firefighters back then were just like modern fire brigades, literally putting out fires.
わしはサラマンダーだからある程度火には強くて、だからあの火事が大変になってるところにも行って、わしがこう率先してこう火を消していくのだ。しゃーしゃーしゃーしゃーって。
Since I'm a salamander, I'm somewhat resistant to fire, so I'd rush to troubled fire scenes and take the initiative to put them out.
そしてわしは纏持（まといもち）というものをやっていたのだ！火消しっていうね、火を消す人たちがいるじゃろ？
And I also served as a "mato-mochi" (standard bearer)!
その中でもその纏っていうね、でっかいね、棒にね、なんか付いててね、古い古い奴があるのだ。それをね持ってね、なのじゃ。
That's the person who carries the big standard pole during firefighting operations to direct the team.
当然人間の寿命よりもわしの寿命の方が長いから、仲良かった人間たちがみんないなくなっちゃって、しばらく1人手いるか〜と思って、その後山に篭ってたのだ。200年ぐらい。
Naturally, my lifespan is longer than a human's, so all my human friends passed away, and after living alone for a while, I decided to seclude myself in the mountains for about 200 years.
山に篭ってる間にしてたこと、寝て起きて食べて寝てたのだ。200年ぐらいずーっと寝て起きて食べて寝ての生活をしていたのだ。
During my time in the mountains, all I did was sleep, wake up, eat, and sleep!
山から降りて人間と一緒に暮らし始めてから今まで20年ぐらい人間と共に生活をしてきたのだ。
After coming down from the mountains and living with humans, I've spent about the last 20 years living alongside them.
人間20年生っていうことじゃの。なんでわしが人間と暮らし始めたかという話なんじゃが、わしが山で生活していた時にの、山にスマホが捨ててあったんじゃよ。
Now, why did I start living with humans? Well, while living in the mountains, I found a discarded smartphone!
「スマホおもれ〜！」と思って触ってたら、わし掲示板、匿名掲示板を発見したんじゃよ。
Thinking "Smartphones are so cool!", I started playing with it and discovered an anonymous bulletin board.
で匿名掲示板で「これ会話できるのでは〜！」と思って、そこに何やら書き込みとかをしてたんだよ。そう人間と話せるの嬉しくて拾ってすぐやり始めたから
Thinking "I can actually talk to people on here!", I started posting right away because I was so happy to talk to humans.
ネットのお作法じゃないけど、その空気感みたいなの全然知らなくて、
I didn't know anything about internet etiquette or the vibe at all,
何をして良くて何がしちゃダメでみたいなの、全然分かんなくて、
so I had no idea what was okay or what was forbidden.
初心者がネットを使いまくって、しかもその場所が
As a total beginner using the internet like crazy—
匿名掲示板とかいうめちゃくちゃ危ない状況になってて、
and worse yet, on an anonymous message board, which is super dangerous—
自演コメントをしたんじゃよ。
I ended up making a sockpuppet comment.
なんか自分をね、守るようなコメントをしたんじゃが、
I posted something to, you know, protect myself.
そしたら、自演がばれる系の掲示板だったっぽくて、他のスレッドとかにも書き込んでたから、
But it turned out to be a board where sockpuppetry gets exposed, and since I posted in other threads too,
そういうのでなんか照合して、IPとかうーん、なんかよくわかんないんだけど、そういうので同一人物ってばれちゃう系のやつで、ぶっ叩かれたのじゃ。
they cross-referenced my IP address—I don't really get it—and since it gave away that I was the same person, I got heavily flamed.
山で拾ったスマホで匿名掲示板を楽しんでいたところ特定・炎上経験あり。
[Memo: Doxxed and flamed after browsing anonymous boards on a phone found in the mountains.]
怖かったー、あれ本当に怖かったのじゃ。
It was so scary... That was genuinely terrifying.
なんか、なんでそんな言うみたいなこといっぱい言われて、
People kept saying all these awful things like, "Why would you do that?"
わしが人間について詳しくないから、なんでそれがダメか分からないじゃろうと思って、
and since I didn't know much about humans, I figured, "Well, I don't know why that's bad."
人間について知りたくて山から降りたのじゃ。
So I came down from the mountain to learn about humans.
そう、人間の父と母に拾ってもらって、あの、人間として育ててもらってのじゃ、
Yeah, human parents picked me up, raised me,
学校も行ったのじゃ、幼稚園とかから通って、
and I even went to school, starting from kindergarten,
人間社会で人間とはなんたるかを学んで、
learning what humans are all about in human society...
人間20年生！
20 years as a human!
人間20年生なのじゃ。
I've been a human for 20 years!
だからこれからはわしが、あの「父」とか「母」とかそういうワードを使う時は、わしのことを育ててくれた人間の「父」「母」を指すと思って欲しいのじゃ。
So from now on, when I use words like "father" or "mother," I want you to know I mean my human adoptive parents who raised me.
そして、今ホロライブに入るまでの人生、サラマンダー生みたいなのをまとめた、「episode 0」という動画がアップロードされていると思うので、
Also, I think there's a video uploaded called "Episode 0" that summarizes my life up until joining Hololive,
もっと気になるよっていう人間たちは、わしのその動画を御覧くださいのじゃー！
so if any humans are curious to know more, please go watch that video!
性格発表しちゃうか！
Time to reveal my personality!
わしは、素で優しいとっても良い子なのじゃ。
I'm naturally kind and an absolute sweetheart.
自認ね。
By my own admission, anyway.
性格は素で優しいとっても良い子(自認)
[Memo: Personality: Naturally kind and an absolute sweetheart (self-proclaimed).]
でね、マネちゃんと初めて会った時、顔合わせみたいなのがあったんじゃよ。
And you know, when I first met my manager, we had a meet-and-greet.
そん時に自己紹介をするじゃろ？そん時に、
During self-introductions, right? At that time, I said,
「わしは優しくて良い子だと思います」って言ったのじゃ。
"I think I'm a kind and good person."
でもね、わし気づいちゃったんじゃがね、
But you know what? I realized...
自分で自分のこと優しいってね、初対面の人間に言う人って、たぶんあんま優しくない！
if someone tells a total stranger they're kind, they're probably not actually that kind!
あのわしさ、シャワー中にさ、割と1日反省会みたいなのをするタイプなんじゃが、
You see, I'm the type to hold a daily self-reflection meeting in the shower,
猛反省したのじゃ。
and I deeply regretted it.
うわー、あれ失言だったなぁー、別にわざわざ自分から、いや良い子ってのは他人のから見い出されるものであって、自分でしかも初手で、なんか自己開示するものではなかったかなぁーと思いながら、
"Ugh, that was such a slip of the tongue," I thought. "Goodness isn't something you declare yourself on day one, especially as self-disclosure..."
髪ワシャワシャって洗ったのじゃ。
while frantically washing my hair.
シャワー中に1日反省会をしたり、相手の気持ちを考えすぎたり繊細な一面を持っている。
[Memo: Tends to reflect in the shower and overthink others' feelings, showing a sensitive side.]
どうしよう、マネちゃんに今わしのことどう思ってるんですかって聞いて、
"What should I do? If I ask my manager right now, 'What do you think of me?'
「い、い、まあ、いい子なんじゃ、ど、どうですかね、自分、自分から言うほどじゃないですかね」とか言われたらどうしようとか思いつつ、
and she says, 'W-Well, you're a good girl, but isn't it weird to say that about yourself?' what would I do?!"
まあ、いっか、しょうがない、しょうがないのじゃ言ってしまったものはね。
Oh well, it can't be helped since I already said it!
本当に良い子なの！だから、
I really am a good girl! So,
あの、お主らがね、こう配信とか動画とかを観て、「ああ、やっぱメラちゃんは本当に良い子だな」って思ったら、どの動画にでもいいから、
if you guys watch my streams or videos and think, "Ah, Mela-gumi really is such a good girl,"
「良い子だね」ってコメント書いてほしいのじゃ。そしたらわしは、
please leave a comment saying "Good girl" on any of my videos! That way, I can think,
次ー！好きなもの！好きなもの3つあるから紹介しちゃおうかな。
Next up! Favorite things! I have three favorites, so let me introduce them.
好きなもの①、人間！
Favorite thing #1: Humans!
なんか人間って個体差すごくない！？あれめっちゃ良いって思うのじゃ！
You know, aren't humans so diverse? I think that's just wonderful!
色んな人間と話して来たんじゃが、なんか全員違うのじゃ！
I've talked to all sorts of humans, and everyone is completely different!
考え方の癖とか、物事の見え方だとかもだし、喋り方違うし、誰と喋ってもおもろいのじゃ！
Their quirks in thinking, how they see things, how they talk—it's so fun no matter who you talk to!
わし本当は全人類と、あの、1on1トークしたいのじゃ。
Honestly, I want to have a 1-on-1 talk with all of humanity.
ダメかのお？
Would that be bad?
喋るのめっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I just love talking so much!
人間が大大好き。個性があるところなどが興味深い。人間と話すのも大好きで、全人類と1on1トークをしてみたい。
[Memo: Loves humans, fascinated by their individuality. Loves talking to people and wants 1-on-1 chats with everyone.]
で、人間と話すの大好きだからこうやってインターネットをね、通して、お主らとコミュニケーション取るのもすごい嬉しいし、
Since I love talking to humans, being able to communicate with you all through the internet makes me so happy.
あとわし人間の言葉がめちゃくちゃ好きで、Twitter（X）を見るのがめちゃくちゃ好きで、特に文字ツイート見るのがめちゃくちゃ好きで、
Also, I love human language so much that I adore browsing Twitter (X), especially reading text tweets!
めら組のツイートとかも見るんじゃが、「この人は何を言うかだし、何を言わないかとかもめっちゃ見てて、
I look at Mela-gumi's tweets too, and I observe what they say and what they choose *not* to say.
このツイートをするってことはこういうことは思ってそうだけど、でもあえてこういうの言わないんじゃなとか、考察するのがめちゃくちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I love analyzing things like, "Posting this probably means they think that, but they purposely left it unsaid, huh?"
生粋のツイッタラー
[Title: Purebred Twitter User]
文字じゃないね、会話も好きでね、
I also like non-text conversations, too,
メンバーと電話するのも好きなのじゃ！面接めっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
like talking on the phone with members! I love interviews so much!
ホロライブのオーディション受けた時も思ったんじゃが、面接って人間めちゃくちゃ構ってくれるんじゃよ、わしに。
Even when I auditioned for Hololive, I thought, "During interviews, humans pay so much attention to me!"
何言っても熱心に聞いてくれるし、しかも場合によっては何人もの人がわしのこと聞いてくれるし、しかも深掘りまでしてくれるのじゃ！「それってこういうことですか？」みたいな。「そうそう！そうなのじゃ！」って思うのじゃ！
No matter what I say, they listen earnestly, and sometimes multiple people listen and even dig deeper, asking, "Do you mean something like this?" And I'm like, "Yes! Exactly that!"
面接週一でしたい！
I want to do interviews once a week!
メンバーとの通話など直接のコミュニケーションも大好き。たくさん構ってもらえる面接も大好きで、週一で受けたい。
[Memo: Loves direct communication like calls with members. Loves getting attention in interviews and wants them weekly.]
好きなもの②、ボカロイド（合成音声）！
Favorite thing #2: Vocaloids (synthesized vocals)!
合成音声大好きなのじゃ！ボカロ曲大好きなのじゃ！
I just love synthesized vocals so much! I love Vocaloid songs!
1日中聴いてる。
I listen to them all day long.
人間と電話しながら、ボカロ曲聴きながら作業してるのじゃ。これがわしの日常。
I work while talking to humans on the phone and listening to Vocaloid songs. That's my daily routine.
好きなボカロPさんいっぱいいるんじゃけど、特にツミキさんっていうボカロPの方がめちゃくちゃ好きで、
I have a lot of favorite Vocaloid producers, but I especially love one named Tsumiki.
好きなアルバム一選、『SAKKAC CRAFT』めちゃくちゃ好きなのじゃ！
My top favorite album pick is "SAKKAC CRAFT"! I love it so much!
めちゃくちゃかっこいいのじゃ！
It's super cool!
わし、あれしか聴いてない！あれしか聴いてないっていうのはこれはあれ、オタクの嘘、オタクの、
I only listen to that! Well, saying I *only* listen to that is an otaku exaggeration, an otaku...
オタク特有の早口
[Title: Otaku-specific fast-talking]
もし「SAKKAC CRAFT」っていうアルバムがガチで大好きなのじゃ。
If the album called "SAKKAC CRAFT" is seriously my absolute favorite!
オーディションの書類審査の時に、「あなたの好きなものについて語ってください」みたいな質問があって、
During the audition document screening, there was a question like "Please talk about things you like," and...
そこでわしがね、書いた文章を今日はね、そのまま貼って良いって言われたから貼っちゃうのじゃ。
so today I was told I could just paste the text I wrote right in, so I'm gonna paste it!
さっきのツミキさんが書いた、これはボカロ曲じゃないんだけど、「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」っていう曲がめちゃくちゃ好きで、その曲について書いてみたのじゃ。
As I mentioned earlier, Tsumiki wrote—well, it's not a Vocaloid song, but "Tokyo Shandy Rendez-Vous" is a song I love so much, and I tried writing about it.
わしのオーディションの時に送った文章を見て欲しいのじゃ。
I want you to see the text I sent for my audition.
どーん！こういう書類はですね、ですます口調で喋ってるのじゃ。
Boom! Documents like this, you see, are written in polite desu-masu tone.
さすがにここでね、タメ語ってやってで喋るとね、常識が無い奴と思われるからなのじゃ。のじゃ略でお送りさせていただいておりますが、
Naturally, if I spoke in casual bantering here, people would think I have no common sense, so I'm using my "no-ja" abbreviation style here, but...
こんな感じで書いて送ったのじゃ！これぐらいわしはボカロ曲そしてボカロPさんが作詞した曲が大好きなのじゃ！
I wrote and sent it like this! That's how much I love Vocaloid songs and songs composed by Vocaloid producers!
そして好きなもの③！なろう系！なろう系めちゃ好きなのじゃ！
And favorite thing #3! Narou-kei light novels! I love Narou-kei light novels so much!
味方が誰も死なない、あんま苦しいハラハラが無いというか、
Where nobody on your side dies, with not too much agonizing suspense, so to speak—
結構ずっと気持ちよく勝ち続けるみたいな、成り上がりって感じじゃから、
it's kind of an ascending story where you just keep winning comfortably, so...
見ててずっと気持ちいいのじゃ。不安な気持ちにならない内容が多いから、
It always feels good to watch. Since there are many plots that don't make you feel anxious,
元気ない時とかに、今日は元気ないからお布団で1日ぐーたらしてようかなって時とかに、
when I have no energy, like on days when I think "I have no energy today, so I'll just laze around in bed all day,"...
ずっとなろう系ばっか読んでるのじゃ。ずっと同じのばっか読んでるのじゃ。
I just read Narou-kei novels the whole time. I just read the same kind of stuff over and over.
なろう系以外にも結構漫画自体が好きで、少年ジャンプの作品とかも結構好きなのじゃ。
Aside from Narou-kei, I also quite like manga in general, and I really like works from Weekly Shonen Jump and such.
アニメとか漫画はね、わしこの辺が好きなのじゃ。
Anime and manga—yeah, these are the ones I like.
怖いもの、発表しようかな！怖いもの①サーモン！
Shall we announce scary things? Scary thing #1: Salmon!
サーモンって怖くないですか？
Isn't salmon scary?
なんかわし、ちっちゃい頃はね、焼き鮭を結構食べてたんじゃよ。で、焼き鮭大好きで、
You see, when I was little, I ate grilled salmon quite a bit. And I loved grilled salmon so much that...
初めて回転寿司に行った時に、わしは英語をちょっと分かってたから、あの「サーモン」って文字を見て「あ、これは鮭じゃ」と思って、
when I went to a conveyor-belt sushi restaurant for the first time, since I understood a little English, I saw the word "salmon" and thought, "Ah, this is sake (salmon/chum salmon)!"
鮭大好きじゃから、この回転寿司でも、あのサーモンとやらを食べてみようではないかと思ってね、こうお皿を取るじゃないですか。
Since I love salmon so much, I thought I'd try eating this "salmon" thing at the conveyor-belt sushi place too, and I grabbed a plate, right?
焼き鮭だと思って、サーモンを食べるじゃないですか。頭がバグって、なんじゃと思って、
Thinking it was grilled salmon, I ate the salmon, right? My brain bugged out, and I thought, "What is this?!"
わしが今まで食べてたあの魚は何処へと思って！そこからずっと怖いのじゃ。
"'Where on earth did the fish I've been eating until now go?!' And ever since then, I've been terrified."
何が起き てるか分かんなくて、なんか「これが来る！」と思って、食べてみたら全然違う。しかも、しかもなんか濡れてた。
Not knowing what was happening, thinking "Here it comes! Here it comes!", I ate it and it was completely different. Plus, plus it was kind of wet.
しっとりしてる。
It was moist.
しばらくはそっからサーモンが食べれなかったのじゃ。怖すぎて。
For a while after that, I couldn't eat salmon. It was too scary.
もう最初から別物だと思って食べれば怖くないと思って、そっからは普通に食べれるのじゃ。
Once I realized I should think of it as a completely different thing from the start, I figured it wouldn't be scary, and since then I can eat it normally.
今では毎回お寿司屋さんに行ったらサーモンを食べるぐらい好きではあるんだよ。好きなんじゃよ。でも、好きだけど怖くて、なんじゃと思いながらいつも食べてるのじゃ。
Nowadays, I like it enough to eat salmon every time I go to a sushi shop. I do like it. But even though I like it, I'm scared, and I always eat it thinking "What on earth is this?"
怖いもの②トースター！
Scary thing #2: Toasters!
これはもう説明不要な気がするのじゃ。トースターって怖くない？
I feel like this doesn't even need explanation. Aren't toasters scary?
わしパン好きなんじゃが、トースターって急に出てきて怖い。「はわわっ」ってなるのじゃ。
I love bread, but toasters suddenly pop out and scare me. I go "Wah-wah-wah!"
焼き上がりました！ヌルヌル〜って出てきてくれたら、わしだって「あ、焼き上がったなー」って思うんじゃが、なんか「ぴょーん！」って出てくるから「はわわっ」ってなるのじゃ。
"'Your toast is ready!' If it just slided out smoothly like nurunuru, I'd be like, 'Ah, it's done,' but because it pops out like pyon!, I go 'Wah-wah-wah!'"
やめてほしい。ジャンプスカエだと思ってる？
Please stop it. Do you think this is a jump scare?
怖いもの③炎上なのだじゃ…炎上ガチで怖いのじゃ…
Scary thing #3: Flame wars... Flame wars are seriously terrifying...
やめて欲しいのじゃ…
I want you to stop...
人生で初めて触ったインターネットで叩かれを経験してるから、めっちゃ過剰に恐れてる気がするのじゃ。初手で山特定されてますからねそしたら。
Having experienced getting flamed on the internet for the very first time in my life, I feel like I'm excessively terrified of it. My mountain was pinpointed right from the start, you see.
「お前住んでる山ここだろ」言われてますからね。ガチ怖かったよアレ。外出れんよ。
People were telling me, "The mountain you live in is right here, isn't it?" That was seriously terrifying. I couldn't go outside.
インターネットってルールとか空気感とかあるじゃろ？あれ初見殺しだと思うのじゃわし。
The internet has rules and a certain vibe, right? I think that's a newbie trap.
アクセスする難易度って低いじゃろ？見るのも楽しく見れるじゃろ？書き込むのも簡単じゃろ？
The barrier to entry for accessing it is low, right? You can enjoy looking at it, right? Posting comments is easy, right?
初めてインターネット触ったのに書き込めたよ？書き込めたのにダメだった…もっとルールとか書いて欲しいよね。「〇〇はこうしてください！」「〇〇しちゃいけません！」みたいなの全部書いて欲しいのじゃ！
Even though it was my very first time touching the internet, I was able to post! Yet even though I could post, it was no good... I wish they'd write out the rules more clearly. I want them to write everything like "Please do this for X!" "You mustn't do Y!"
だからすっごい気を使おうと思うのじゃ。ひけしやじゃし。
That's why I try to be extremely careful. I'm a fire extinguisher, after all.
わしの夢！わしの夢は人間に恩返しをすることなのだじゃ。
My dream! My dream is to repay kindness to humans.
人間として20年間生きてきて、仲間に入れてもらえたのがめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったのじゃ。
Having lived as a human for 20 years, I was so incredibly happy to be accepted into a group of friends.
200年ぐらいずっとひとりぼっちだったし、ずっと寂しかったから、構ってもらえたのがすごく嬉しくて人間好きなのじゃ。
For about 200 years I was all alone and always lonely, so I was so happy when people paid attention to me, and I love humans.
わしもかつてのわしみたいに今居場所がなくて1人で寂しいって思ってる人間がもしかしたらいるかもしれないと思って、わしはそんな人間の居場所になりたいのじゃ。
Thinking there might be humans out there who, just like my former self, currently have no place to belong and feel lonely all by themselves, I want to become a place of belonging for such people.
次はわしがね、居場所になることによって人間に恩を返していくという作戦なのだじゃ。
Next, my strategy is to repay kindness to humans by becoming that place of belonging myself.
そしてインターネットでやっぱわしあのかつて痛い目に遭いましたから、どんな人間にも優しい、インターネット1年生でもね、初心者の方々でもね、入りやすいそんな配信や動画を作りたいのじゃ。
And since I had a painful experience on the internet in the past, I want to create streams and videos that are kind to any human, welcoming even to internet first-graders and beginners.
あったかい居場所にしたいのじゃ。
I want to make it a warm place of belonging.
いかがだったでしょうか？わしの自己紹介動画見て、熱干しめらというサラマンダーがどんな子なのかちょっとは分かってくれたかのかのぉ？
How was it? Did my self-introduction video help you understand a little bit about what kind of creature "Natsuboshi Mera" the salamander is?
これから配信とか動画とか見て、もっといろんなわしのことを知っていって欲しいなとは思いつつ、この自己紹介動画さえ見れば、
While I hope you'll watch my streams and videos from now on and get to know all sorts of things about me, as long as you watch this self-introduction video...
ま、あちちめら、9割ぐらい分かったと言っても
Well, even if I said I understood about 90%,
過言ではないぐらいな内容な気がする
I feel like it wouldn't be an exaggeration.
過言か？過言かあ
An exaggeration? An exaggeration.
楽しんでもらえたなら幸いなのじゃ！
If you enjoyed it, I'd be happy!
そして最後に一言、
And finally, one word,
わし運命を信じてるのじゃ。
I believe in destiny.
人生ってさ、その時その時で出会うべき人がいるじゃないですか？
In life, aren't there people you're supposed to meet at certain times?
それがお主にとってのその時出会うべきだった人がわしじゃったら良いなってすごく思うんじゃよ
I really hope that the person you were supposed to meet at that time is me.
あちちめらと出会ってから、すごい毎日楽しくなって、居場所になったよ
Ever since I met you guys, every day has become so fun, and it became a place where I belong.
って思ってくれる人間が1人でもいっぱいいたらわしはここに来た意味があったなって思うし
If even a single person feels that way, I'll feel like coming here had meaning,
そうなるようにこれからお主にとっての温かい居場所になることを願って活動していきます！
and hoping to become a warm place for you going forward, I'll keep streaming!
チャンネル登録とか高評価とかコメントとかいろんな方法でわしのこと応援してくれるととっても嬉しいのじゃ！
I'd be so happy if you support me through channel subscriptions, likes, and comments!
そしてデビュー記念ボイスとかデビューにあたっていろんなものが販売中なのでこちらも興味があったらチェックしてみて欲しいのじゃ！
Also, debut voice packs and items are on sale, so please check them out if you're interested!
ということで今日の動画はおしまいなのじゃ！
With that, today's video comes to an end!
また動画とか配信とかいろんなところでのお主と会えると嬉しいのじゃ！
I'd be happy to see you in videos, streams, and all sorts of places!
これからよろしくね！
Thank you for your support!
ということでまた次の何かでお会いしましょー！
So with that, let's meet again in some future video or stream!
ばいばいのじゃー！
Bye-bye!